[Music]
when you purchase a house the lender
will typically offer you mortgage
insurance
but there's a better alternative
purchasing a personal life insurance
policy
is almost always a better product at a
better price let's discuss
four main reasons for choosing a
personal life policy over mortgage
insurance
first the cost of a personal term life
insurance policy is typically 20 to 30
percent less
than mortgage insurance not only is it
cheaper but you maintain your coverage
amount throughout the whole policy
lifetime whereas mortgage insurance
will only pay out what's left on your
mortgage second
life insurance assesses your eligibility
at time of application
whereas mortgage insurance does so after
death
ultimately this means that your family
will receive the money
sooner with a life insurance policy
third
life insurance is more portable mortgage
insurance requires that you reapply
every time you move houses or renew your
mortgage
with life insurance your policy follows
you from lender to lender
and from house to house so you don't
have to worry about your health
or your age affecting the price lastly
life insurance provides you with more
financial options
with mortgage insurance the bank is the
beneficiary and they will use the money
to pay off your mortgage
that's it with life insurance you get to
pick the beneficiaries
and between your will your financial
advisor
and your loved ones you can create a
plan to use the money
as you wish you can cover debts pay your
monthly expenses
and invest the rest to make even more
money for the future
so if you currently have mortgage
insurance don't hesitate to reach out to
your brokers for more information
about how billiard insurance group can
make sure we not only save you money
but also get you the best policy that
fits you and your family's needs now
and into the future
[Music]
you